<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MS Teams on Cezary Piątek Blog</title>
    <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/ms-teams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MS Teams on Cezary Piątek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:21:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/ms-teams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be the first to know of the bug</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/be-the-first-to-know-of-the-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:21:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/be-the-first-to-know-of-the-bug/</guid>
      <description>Over a year ago I heard for the first time about the ELK stack. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve had an opportunity to help five teams to implements ELK as a part of their development process (one team is using it on production, the rest of them so far only in development environment). ELK stands for ElasticSearch-Logstash-Kibana and it&amp;rsquo;s a set of services that helps to improve productivity in the area of logging, covering aspects of collecting, processing, storing and presenting log data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating TeamCity with Microsoft Teams using PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/integrating-teamcity-with-msteams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:05:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/integrating-teamcity-with-msteams/</guid>
      <description>With the beginning of new year I joined a new team where I help with project bootstrapping. I&amp;rsquo;ve been configuring TeamCity, Gitlab and webservers. It&amp;rsquo;s the first time for me to work with Gitlab, so I started looking around and checking what opportunities come to me with that tool. One of my discoveries was the &amp;ldquo;Integration&amp;rdquo; bookmark, allowing me to connect Gitlab with other systems. I checked a list of possible integrations and found that it could communicate with Microsoft Teams chat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
