<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mocks on Cezary Piątek Blog</title>
    <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/mocks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mocks on Cezary Piątek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:10:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/mocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The fastest way to create WireMock.NET mappings</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/generate-wiremocknet-mappings-with-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:10:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/generate-wiremocknet-mappings-with-proxy/</guid>
      <description>In my journey through the nuances of API testing, I&amp;rsquo;ve often encountered the challenges and time-consuming aspects of creating accurate WireMock mappings. As developers, we often get bogged down in the details of the anatomy of inter-service communication, not to mention the frustrating typos that lead to inaccurate mappings. In this blog post, I will introduce a powerful solution: the WireMock.NET proxy. This feature completely changes the way we approach mapping preparation, significantly reducing both workload and debugging time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mocking GraphQL queries with WireMock.NET</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-graphql-with-wiremock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:10:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-graphql-with-wiremock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GraphQL is a query language for APIs that allows clients to request exactly what they need, making data retrieval more efficient than traditional REST APIs. It supports three different types of client-server interaction: queries, mutations and subscriptions. When you start integrating a GraphQL API as a consumer in your application, it&amp;rsquo;s likely that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to write automated tests to ensure that the integration works correctly. In this blog post, I will show you how to mock GraphQL queries using WireMock.NET.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WireMock.NET - Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-outgoing-http-requests-p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:10:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-outgoing-http-requests-p2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second installment of my blog post series on WireMock.NET, I will be discussing some of the most common problems that developers encounter while using the library. WireMock troubleshooting can be quite time consuming, especially when you don&amp;rsquo;t know the drill. I hope that my guideline will save you a lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WireMock.NET - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-outgoing-http-requests-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:10:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-outgoing-http-requests-p1/</guid>
      <description>In my previous blog post, I discussed the use of dependency injection (DI) containers for mocking dependencies in tests for ASP.NET Core applications. While this approach is useful in some cases, I personally prefer using mocks/stubs/fakes that don&amp;rsquo;t require any changes in the app internals and work directly with the actual protocol used by the application being tested.&#xA;In this post, I will introduce to you WireMock.NET, a powerful tool for mocking HTTP requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mocking dependencies in ASP.NET Core tests</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-dependencies-in-asp-net-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:21:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/mocking-dependencies-in-asp-net-core/</guid>
      <description>As I recently spent some time writing and refactoring tests that utilize WebApplicationFactory, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to have some thoughts and ideas for improvement that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the process of mocking dependencies in a DI container when using WebApplicationFactory, and offer some insights and best practices I&amp;rsquo;ve learned along the way. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned pro or new to unit testing ASP.NET Core applications, I hope this information will be helpful as you work to simplify and streamline your tests.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
