<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>architecture on Cezary Piątek Blog</title>
    <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in architecture on Cezary Piątek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:18:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I don&#39;t use MediatR for CQRS</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/why-i-dont-use-mediatr-for-cqrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:18:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/why-i-dont-use-mediatr-for-cqrs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this article is not to criticize the MediatR library. MediatR is a tool - and just like any tool, it has its own scope of application, and being used incorrectly might do more harm than good. This blog post summarizes my thoughts about using MediatR for supporting CQRS architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exception usage analyzer</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/exceptions-usages-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/exceptions-usages-analyzer/</guid>
      <description>Over a year ago I wrote a blog post about designing exceptions. I found this article very useful by myself and I used it as a reference a few times during code review. However, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to expect that, after reading the recommended resource, anybody would start to apply described rules immediately and remember about them all the time. It&amp;rsquo;s a learning process and it takes some time. A while ago I got interested with Roslyn (I even delivered a public presentation about it - polish recording available here) and there is a really cool thing about Roslyn analyzers that can solve this problem - they help to actively introduce best practices into your codebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The art of designing exceptions</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/the-art-of-designing-exceptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/the-art-of-designing-exceptions/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been in a situation when you discovered an exception in the logs that forced you to spend the next couple of minutes - or even hours - figuring out what exactly went wrong? The message was very cryptic and the only useful information that guided you to the crime scene was a stack trace. And after arriving there, you still had no idea what had really happened and what was the culprit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CQRS snippets</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/cqrs-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:20:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/cqrs-snippets/</guid>
      <description>A year ago, during my trip to one of Software developer conferences, I got a lot of opportunities to discuss variety of topics related to software architecture. Most of them concerned CQRS and CQS patterns. I heard about them many times before but I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a chance to use them in practice. After getting back from the conference, I decided to give it a shot and try to introduce it in one of my private projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
