<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GithubActions on Cezary Piątek Blog</title>
    <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/githubactions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GithubActions on Cezary Piątek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:21:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/githubactions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding support for VisualStudio 2022 to your extension</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/migrate-vsix-to-vs2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:21:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/migrate-vsix-to-vs2022/</guid>
      <description>I published my first VisualStudio extension on 26th February 2018. It was initially created for Visual Studio 2017, but a few months later Visual Studio 2019 came out and I needed to support it as I was one of the beneficent. The migration was straightforward: it required only to extend InstallationTarget range to [15.0,17.0) in vsixmanifest, re-compile, and of course, re-publish the extension to the Visual Studio marketplace. Recently, the Visual Studio 2022 Preview was published.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Github Actions for Visual Studio Extension developers</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/develop-vsextension-with-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 10:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/develop-vsextension-with-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>I discovered the power of Roslyn over three years ago and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve developed three Visual Studio extensions and a couple of code analyzers. Because I work on those tools only in my free time, the word &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo; is a key here, so automation really matters. So far I&amp;rsquo;ve been using AppVeyor for building and testing my extensions. However, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of integrated solutions because they require much less work for setup, and since GithubActions became generally available I wanted to give it a try.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
