<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Powershell on Cezary Piątek Blog</title>
    <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Powershell on Cezary Piątek Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:05:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cezarypiatek.github.io/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating TeamCity with Microsoft Teams using PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/integrating-teamcity-with-msteams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:05:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/integrating-teamcity-with-msteams/</guid>
      <description>With the beginning of new year I joined a new team where I help with project bootstrapping. I&amp;rsquo;ve been configuring TeamCity, Gitlab and webservers. It&amp;rsquo;s the first time for me to work with Gitlab, so I started looking around and checking what opportunities come to me with that tool. One of my discoveries was the &amp;ldquo;Integration&amp;rdquo; bookmark, allowing me to connect Gitlab with other systems. I checked a list of possible integrations and found that it could communicate with Microsoft Teams chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring PowerShell with graphical user interface.</title>
      <link>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/exploring-powershell-with-gui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 10:34:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cezarypiatek.github.io/post/exploring-powershell-with-gui/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently watched a pretty decent tutorial about DSC on Microsoft Virtual Academy. I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of video tutorials because it always takes more time to watch them than read a book/blog post (you can hack it by increasing video speed and save yourself a couple of minutes) but sometimes there is additional beneficial side effect - the presenter can show you (accidentally or not) some tips and tricks not strictly related to the core subject of the video.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>